Colin Arndt

Data Scientist & Quantitative Analyst | San Diego, CA 3858.281.3748 ■ colinfarndt@gmail.com • colinarndt • colinarndt

SUMMARY

Data science professional skilled in transforming raw data into meaningful information using data-oriented programming languages and visualization software, extracting and analyzing information from large structured and unstructured datasets using data mining, data modeling, natural language processing, and machine learning. Quantitative strategies to inform securities investing, equities investing, pricing, or valuation of financial instruments and statistical models for risk management, asset optimization or relative value analysis. Collaborative team player with ownership mentality and a track record of delivering the highest quality strategic solutions to resolve challenges and propel business growth, honed through extensive experience in computer information systems and management.

EDUCATION

M.S. Data Science and Financial Technology

University of London

Sonoma State University

B.A. Psychology

Sept. 2002 - May 2007

Oct. 2020 - Sept. 2022

Cotati. CA

Remote

PROJECTS

Asset Correlations before and after the COVID-19 Crash

- · Quantified the post-COVID spike in asset correlations using Python, Numpy and Pandas
- Validated price data from open-source yfinance library by creating a web scraper in BeautifulSoup
- Visualized results using Heatmaps with Seaborn and Rolling correlation window plots with Matplotlib

Detecting Counterfeit Bank Notes using Supervised K-means Clustering Implementing n-fold Cross Validation K-nearest Neighbor Classification from Scratch

EXPERIENCE

Marketing & Analytics (Business Intelligence)

Pilates on Harrison

Nov. 2018 - May 2021

Remote

- Offered partnership share in recognition of outstanding contributions to business
- · Advised successful transition to online service delivery during COVID crisis, with no loss in monthly revenue
- Implemented client surveys, processing results from 200+ responses with key conclusions

Computer Support Specialist / Manager

Nov. 2015 - Sept. 2019

mac tonic

C3 IT Solutions

Eugene, OR

- Promoted to management as a result of leadership and technical skills
- Slashed diagnostic procedure times, yielding 25% increase in service profits
- Overhauled service documentation system resulting in 20% increase in staff efficiency

Computer Support Specialist

Sept. 2007 - Nov. 2015

Madison, WI

- · Consulted on solutions for data backups and security, virtualization, kiosk devices, VPNs and more
- Developed front-end websites in WordPress and Drupal with ecommerce and CRM functionality
- Provided Search Engine Optimization and Online Reputation Management services